这里是二零二四年湖北省初中学业水平考试
英语试题听力部分。
该部分分为四个大题，共二十个小题。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束。
前，请将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
第一节：听短对话，选择图片。
下面你将听到五段短对话，根据你所听到的内容，选出与你所听内容相符
的图片。
听完每段对话后。
你将有五秒钟的时间作答，每段对话听一遍。
Text 1 Come on!
The dragon boat race has begun!
Wow! How exciting!
Text 2 Bob, dinner is ready.
Wait a moment, I'm working on a math problem.
Text 3 Hi, Xiaofen.
Did you watch the soccer game last night?
Hush, Nancy. We must be quiet in the library.
Text 4 Look!
Liu Ming is flying a kite with his friends.
Oh! His pet dog is running with them.
It's funny. Text 5 Miss White, I've had a toothache for two days.
6 Take it easy.
Lie down and open your mouth.
第二节：听短对话，选择答案。
下面你将听到五段短对话。
听完每段对话后，你将有十秒钟的时间作答和阅读下一小题。
每段。
话听两遍。
Text 6 Excuse me, Mr.
How do you read this word?
Ruler Ruler. Got it.
There is a ruler in my pencil box.
Excuse me, Mr.
Wilson. How do you read this word?
Ruler Ruler. Got it.
There is a ruler in my pencil box.
Text 7 Eric, get up.
What time is it?
A quarter past seven.
It's too late.
But school starts at eight.
It's my turn to clean the classroom today.
I have no time for breakfast.
Take the sandwich and milk with you.
Thanks, Mom. Bye.
Eric, get up.
What time is it?
A quarter past seven.
It's too late.
But school starts at eight.
It's my turn to clean the classroom today.
I have no time for breakfast.
Take the sandwich and milk with you.
Thanks, Mom. Bye.
8 Let's see a movie, David.
Sounds good. What about Chinese cartoons?
I'm glad you like them.
Here are Mulan, Nezha,
and The Monkey King.
Which one do you like?
I like Nezha.
Shall we watch it?
Okay. Let's see a movie, David.
Sounds good. What about Chinese cartoons?
I'm glad you like them.
Here are Mulan, Nezha,
and The Monkey King.
Which one do you like?
I like Nezha.
Shall we watch it?
Okay. Text 9 Excuse me, sir.
I'm Jane. I live next door to you.
Oh, nice to meet you, Jane.
I'm Alan. Nice to meet you too, Alan.
I'm new here.
I'm wondering if there is a supermarket near here.
There's one on Center Street behind the park.
Thanks a lot.
10 me, sir.
I'm Jane. I live next door to you.
Oh, nice to meet you, Jane.
I'm Alan. Nice to meet you too, Alan.
I'm new here.
I'm wondering if there is a supermarket near here.
There's one on Center Street behind the park.
Thanks a lot.
Text 10 Morning.
This is room 206.
I'll take the train to Beijing tomorrow morning.
Could you please call a taxi for me?
No problem, madam.
is your train?
At 910. It takes about half an hour to the station from here.
I'll ask the driver to pick you up at 8 o 'clock.
Is that okay?
Great. Thanks. Morning.
This is room 206.
I'll take the train to Beijing tomorrow morning.
Could you please call a taxi for me?
No problem, madam.
When is your train?
At 910. It takes about half an hour to the station from here.
I'll ask the driver to pick you up at 8 o Is that okay?
Great. Thanks. Text Morning.
This 206. for Text 11
第三节：听长对话选择答案。
下面你将听到三段长对话。
听每段对话前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完。
每段对话后，每小题你有五秒钟的时间作答。
每段对话听两遍。
听第一段长对话，回答第十一至十二小题。
Thanks for taking me shopping, Rose.
You are welcome, Jack.
This shop has lots of nice clothes.
Great. It's so cold here.
I need winter clothes.
That's true. We get snow tomorrow.
You have to wear warm clothes.
Okay. Let's look at coats first.
What size do you wear?
Large, usually. Try this one on.
It looks cool.
Um, I like it.
It's comfortable and the price is good.
I'll take it.
I also need a sweater and a scarf.
We can go to another store to get them.
have a lot of shopping to do.
You do. And I'm happy to help.
Thanks for taking me shopping, Rose.
You are welcome, Jack.
This shop has lots of nice clothes.
Great. It's so cold here.
I need winter clothes.
That's true. We get snow tomorrow.
You have to wear warm clothes.
Okay. Let's look at coats first.
What size do you wear?
Large, usually. Try this one on.
It looks cool.
Um, I like it.
It's comfortable and the price is good.
I'll take it.
I also need a sweater and a scarf.
We can go to another store to get them.
I have a lot of shopping to do.
You do. And I'm happy to help.
听第二段长对话，回答第十三至十四小题。
Text 12. Mario, let's find a good place for camping.
How about over there, by the water?
We need water for cooking and cleaning.
That's true. But it's not safe by the water.
Maybe we shouldn't camp there.
How about a place close to those rocks?
The ground is not smooth enough for camping there.
Oh, you are right, Kathy.
I didn't notice that.
Ha The place where we are standing is pretty good.
It's nice and smooth, and there are some big trees around.
We can camp under the trees.
It will be comfortable to sleep here.
That's it. Mario, let's find a good place for camping.
How about over there, by the water?
We need water for cooking and cleaning.
That's true. But it's not safe by the water.
Maybe we shouldn't camp there.
How about a place close to those rocks?
The ground is not smooth enough for camping there.
Oh, you are right, Kathy.
I didn't notice that.
Ha The place where we are standing is pretty good.
It's nice and smooth, and there are some big trees around.
We can camp under the trees.
It will be comfortable to sleep here.
That's it. Hey, I'm the Hi, Linda.
听第三段长对话，回答第十五至十七小题。
I'm planning a trip to Hubei, and I'm looking up some information online.
I visited Hubei several years ago.
Really? Tell me something about it.
There are lots of rivers, and mountains, such as the East Lake, the Yangtze River,
and Mount Wudang Shan.
Sounds great. Anything else?
Yes. There are also many places of great interest, like the Yellow Crane Tower.
You visited the Yellow Crane Tower?
Right. It stands by the Yangtze River.
From the top of the tower, the river looks more wonderful.
Fantastic. I'd like to go.
Did you visit any museums?
Of course. I've been to the Hubei Provincial Museum.
It's a famous one in China.
Oh, I like history, and visiting museums is my favorite.
By the way, don't miss the delicious local food, hot dry noodles, and wuchang fish.
Thanks. I can't wait to go there.
Hey, James, what are you doing?
Hi, Linda. I'm planning a trip to Hubei, and I'm looking up some information online.
I visited Hubei several years ago.
Really? Tell me something about it.
There are lots of lakes, rivers, and mountains, such as the East Lake, the Yangtze
River, and Mount Wudang Shan.
Sounds great. Anything else?
Yes. There are also many places of great interest, like the Yellow Crane Tower.
You visited the Yellow Crane Tower?
Right. It stands by the Yangtze River.
From the top of the tower, the river looks more wonderful.
Fantastic. I'd like to go.
Did you visit any museums?
Of course. I've been to the Hubei Provincial Museum.
It's a famous one in China.
Oh, I like history, and visiting museums is my favorite.
By the way, don't miss the delicious local food, hot dry noodles, and wuchang fish.
Thanks. I can't wait to go there.
第四节：听短文，填写表格。
下面你将听到一段短文，
根据你所听到的内容填写表格中所缺单词，每空仅填一词。
听短文前，你将有十五秒钟的时间浏览表格；
听完后，你将有十五秒钟的时间作答。
短文听两。
short text twice.
10. Listen twice.
twice. 12. twice.
twice. 14. Listen the short text twice.
Listen the short text twice.
We also play the guitar.
We always have a good time.
Our parents often come to watch our music shows and take photos of us.
Here is a picture of our latest show.
It's me with the pink hat.
I look cute, don't I?
The music club can be hard when I have to remember the words and follow the music.
But it helps me understand more about music and makes me relaxed.
used to be shy when I was in a show.
Now I'm brave enough to talk and sing in front of people.
Our music club is cool.
Will you join us?
Hello, my name is Sally.
Welcome to our music club.
This is Mrs.
our music teacher.
She is very nice and always has great ideas.
And these are my good friends at the club.
We learn to sing and dance to fun songs.
We also play the guitar.
We always have a good time.
Our parents often come to watch our music shows and take photos of us.
Here is a picture of our latest show.
It's me with the pink hat.
I look cute, don't I?
The music club can be hard when I have to remember the words and follow the music.
But it helps me understand more about music and makes me relaxed.
I used to be shy when I was in a show.
Now I'm brave enough to talk and sing in front of people.
Our music club is cool.
Will you join us?
现在，请将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。